<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2014 Your Name <name@emailaddress.com> -->
<application>
<id type="desktop">fotoxx.desktop</id>
<metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
<summary>Fotoxx is a free open source Linux program for photo editing and collection management. The goal is to meet most user needs while remaining fast and easy to use. 
<!--Brief summary of application.e.g. for Inkscape "Create and edit Scalable Vector Graphics images"-->
</summary>
<description>
<!-- One or two paras about the application. Only <p> <ul> <ol> and <li> can be used-->
<!-- see http://people.freedesktop.org/~hughsient/appdata/#description for style details-->
<p>Navigate a large image collection using a thumbnail browser, click on an image to view or edit. A rich set of edit and retouch functions is available (see examples below). Import RAW files and edit with deep color. Save revised images as JPEG, BMP, PNG (8/16 bits), or TIFF (8/16). Select an object or area within an image (freehand outline, follow edges, select matching tones, ... ), apply edit functions, copy and paste, resize, blend, warp, etc. without using layers. Edit functions have fast feedback using the full image. Add metadata (tags, geotags, dates, ratings, captions ...) to images. Search images using any metadata and/or folder and file names or partial names. Batch functions are available for renaming, adding metadata, moving, resizing. Fotoxx uses your image files wherever they are and maintains a separate index for fast searching. Fotoxx is standards compliant and can be used with other photo edit programs (no lock-in). Fotoxx is easy to use but unconventional, so please read the user manual (at least a few pages) before jumping in.

</p>
</description>
<url type="homepage">http://www.kornelix.com/fotoxx.html</url>
<screenshots>
<screenshot type="default">http://www.kornelix.com/uploads/1/3/0/3/13035936/7552915_orig.jpg<!--http://projectname/screenshot.png--></screenshot>
<!--<screenshot type="default">http://projectname/screenshot.png</screenshot>-->
<!--<screenshot type="default">http://projectname/screenshot.png</screenshot>-->
</screenshots>
</application>
