<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>kanagram.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <name>Kanagram</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">Kanagram</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">Kanagram</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">Kanagram</name>
  <name xml:lang="hu">Kanagram</name>
  <name xml:lang="nds">Kanagram</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">Kanagram</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">Kanagram</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">Kanagram</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">Kanagram</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">Kanagram</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Kanagram</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">Kanagram</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxKanagramxx</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-TW">語言_Kanagram</name>
  <summary>Letter Order Game</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="cs">Hra uspořádání písmen</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Juego de ordenación de letras</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">Kirjainten järjestyspeli</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="hu">Betűsorrend játék</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nds">Bookstaven ornen</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Letters ordenen</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Gra w układanie słów</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Jogo de Ordenação de Letras</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Jogo de ordenação de letras</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Hra o usporiadaní písmen</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Bokstavsordningsspel</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Гра з впорядкування літер</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxLetter Order Gamexx</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-TW">字母排序遊戲</summary>
  <description>
    <p>Kanagram is a game based on anagrams of words: the puzzle is solved when the letters of the scrambled word are put back in the correct order. There is no limit on either time taken, or the amount of attempts to solve the word. It features several included word lists, a hints-and-cheats help system, a word list editor, and allows for updating and distributing wordlists via KNewStuff. The interface is scalable and appropriate for children.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Kanagram on anagrammeihin perustuva peli: peli on ratkaistu, kun sanan sekoitetut kirjaimet on laitettu takaisin oikeille paikoilleen. Peli ei rajoita ratkaisemiseen kuluvaa aikaa eikä ratkaisuyrityksiä. Peliin kuuluu useita sanastoja, vihjeet sekä huijaamismahdollisuus ja sanastojen muokkaus. Sanastoja voi myös päivittää ja jakaa verkkoon KNewStuffin välityksellä. Käyttöliittymä on skaalautuva ja sopii lapsille.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nds">Kanagram is Speel, dat op Woort-Anagramms opbuut: Dat Radel is lööst, wenn de Bookstaven in de richtige Reeg brocht wöörn. Dat gifft keen Grenz för de Tiet, de een bruukt, un ok nich för de Tall vun Versöök. Dat gifft en Reeg mitlevert Wöörlisten, en Tipps- un Tricks-Hülpsysteem un en Woortlisteditor. De Woortlisten laat sik över KNewStuff opfrischen un verdelen. De Böversiet lett sik ok vun Kinners bruken.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Kanagram is een spel gebaseerd op anagrammen van woorden: de puzzel is opgelost wanneer de letters van het door elkaar gegooide woord terug zijn geplaatst in de juiste volgorde. Er is geen limiet aan ofwel de genomen tijd of het aantal pogingen om het woord op te lossen. Het biedt verschillende meegeleverde woordlijsten, een tips-en-vals-spelen helpsysteem, een bewerker van woordlijsten en maakt het mogelijk woordlijsten bij te werken en te verspreiden via KNewStuff. Het interface is schaalbaar en geschikt voor kinderen.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Kanagram jest grą opartą na anagramach słów: układanka jest uznana za rozwiązaną gdy litery z rozbitego słowa zostaną ustawione w poprawnej kolejności. Nie ma ograniczenia na czas ani na liczbę prób ułożenia słowa. Program zawiera kilka sposób słów, system pomocy i podpowiedzi, edytor spisu słów, a także umożliwia uaktualnianie i rozprowadzanie spisu słów poprzez KNewStuff. Układ sterowania programem jest skalowany i przystosowany dla dzieci.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O Kanagram é um jogo baseado nos anagramas de palavras: o 'puzzle' fica resolvido quando as letras da palavra baralhada forem colocadas na ordem correcta. Não existe nenhum limite para o tempo tomado ou para a quantidade de tentativas de resolução da palavra. Oferece diversas listas de palavras já incluídas, um sistema de ajuda por sugestões e batotas, um editor de listas de palavras, assim como a actualização e distribuição das listas de palavras através do KNewStuff. A interface é ajustável e apropriada para crianças.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Kanagram é um jogo baseado em anagramas de palavras: o puzzle é solucionado quando as letras da palavra embaralhada forem colocadas na ordem correta. Não existe nenhum limite de tempo ou quantidade de tentativas de resolução da palavra. Oferece diversas listas de palavras já incluídas, um sistema de ajuda por dicas e truques, um editor de listas de palavras, assim como a atualização e distribuição das listas de palavras através do KNewStuff. A interface é ajustável e apropriada para crianças.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Kanagram je gra založená na anagramoch slov: skladačka sa vyrieši, keď písmená rozbitého slova sa poskladajú v správnom poradí. Nie je žiadny obmedzenie v čase ani v počte pokusov na vyriešenie slova. Obsahuje niekoľko zoznamov slov, systém rád a pomôcok, editor zoznamu slov a umožní aktualizáciu a distribúciu zoznamu slov cez KNewStuff. Rozhranie je škálovateľné a vhodné pre deti.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Kanagram är ett spel baserat på anagram av ord: pusslet är löst när bokstäverna i det hopblandade ordet är placerade i rätt ordning. Det finns varken någon gräns för hur lång tid det får ta, eller hur många försök som får göras för att lösa ordet. Funktioner som ingår är flera olika ordlistor, ett hjälpsystem med tips och fusk, en editor av ordlistor, och det tillåter att ordlistor uppdateras och distribueras via Heta nyheter. Gränssnittet är skalbart och lämpligt för barn.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">KAnagram — це гра, що заснована на розгадуванні анаграм: загадку буде розгадано, якщо розташувати переплутані літери слова у правильному порядку. Обмежень на час розв’язання немає, так само як і на кількість спроб вгадати слово. До пакунка KAnagram вже включено декілька словників підготованих для гри, але набагато більше таких словників ви можете знайти у інтернеті. У програмі передбачено систему підказок, редактор списків слів. Інтерфейс програми є масштабованим та адаптованим для дітей.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxKanagram is a game based on anagrams of words: the puzzle is solved when the letters of the scrambled word are put back in the correct order. There is no limit on either time taken, or the amount of attempts to solve the word. It features several included word lists, a hints-and-cheats help system, a word list editor, and allows for updating and distributing wordlists via KNewStuff. The interface is scalable and appropriate for children.xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">Kanagram 是一套字詞遊戲：將單字字母順序打亂，並將它排回正確的順序。沒有限制解題的時間或次數。它並且提供了一些功能，例如單字清單，提示系統，單字清單編輯器，並允許透過 KNewStuff 更新或散布。介面設計適合小朋友。</p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">http://edu.kde.org/kanagram/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=kanagram</url>
  <url type="help">http://docs.kde.org/stable/en/kdeedu/kanagram/index.html</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>http://kde.org/images/screenshots/kanagram.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <provides>
    <binary>kanagram</binary>
  </provides>
</component>
