<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>klettres.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <name>KLettres</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">KLettres</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">KLettres</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">KLettres</name>
  <name xml:lang="hu">KLettres</name>
  <name xml:lang="lt">KLettres</name>
  <name xml:lang="nds">KLettres</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">KLettres</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">KLettres</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">KLettres</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">KLettres</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">KLettres</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Klettres</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">KLettres</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxKLettresxx</name>
  <summary>Learn The Alphabet</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="cs">Výuka abecedy</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Aprende el alfabeto</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">Opi aakkoset</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="hu">Tanulja meg az ABC-t</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="lt">Išmokite abėcėlę</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nds">Dat Alfabeet lehren</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Leer het alfabet</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Nauka alfabetu</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Aprender o Alfabeto</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Aprenda o alfabeto</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Výuka abecedy</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Inlärning av alfabetet</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Вивчення абетки</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxLearn The Alphabetxx</summary>
  <description>
    <p>KLettres is an application specially designed to help the user to learn an alphabet in a new language and then to learn to read simple syllables. The user can be a young child aged from two and a half or an adult that wants to learn the basics of a foreign language. There are currently 25 languages available: Arabian, Brazilian Portuguese, Czech, Danish, Dutch, British English, US English, Phonics English, French, German, Hebrew, Hugarian, Italian, Kannada, Low Saxon, Malayalam, Norwegian Bokmål, Punjabi, Luganda, Romanized Hindi, Russian, Spanish, Slovak, Telugu and Ukrainian. KLettres provides a special user interface and themes for younger users.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">KLettres on sovellus, joka on suunniteltu erityisesti auttamaan käyttäjää oppimaan uuden kielen aakkoset ja oppimaan sitten lukemaan yksinkertaisia tavuja. Käyttäjä voi olla kaksi ja puoli -vuotiaasta lapsesta aikuiseen, joka haluaa oppia vieraan kielen perusteet. Tällä hetkellä on saatavilla 25 kieltä: alasaksa, amerikanenglanti, arabia, brasilianportugali, brittienglanti, englannin äänteet, espanja, ganda, heprea, hollanti, italia, kannada, latinaistettu hindi, malajalam, norjan bokmål, pandžabi, ranska, saksa, slovakki, tanska, telugu, tšekki, ukraina, unkari ja venäjä. KLettresissä on nuorempia käyttäjiä varten oma käyttöliittymä ja teemoja.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nds">KLettres is en Programm, dat Brukers hölpt, dat Alfabet in en nieg Spraak to lehren un denn ok eenfach Sülven in disse Spraak to lesen. De Bruker kann en lütt Blaag vun tweeenhalf Johr oder en Opwussen wesen, de dat Grundweten vun en nieg Spraak lehren will. Opstunns sünd 25 Spraken verföögbor: Araabsch, Brasiliaansch Portugeesch, Tschechsch, Däänsch, Nedderlannsch, Britsch Engelsch, US Engelsch, Foneetsch Engelsch, Franzöösch, Hoochdüütsch, Hebrääsch, Ungaarsch, Italieensch, Kannadaansch, Plattdüütsch, Malayalaamsch, Norweegsch (Bokmål), Pandschaabsch, Lugandsch, Romaniseert Hindi, Russ'sch, Spaansch, Slowaaksch, Telugu un Ukrainsch. KLetrres hett en besünner Böversiet un Mustern för jünger Brukers.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">KLettres is een toepassing speciaal ontworpen om de gebruiker te helpen bij het leren van het alfabet van een nieuwe taal en daarna het leren lezen van eenvoudige zinnen. De gebruiker kan een jong kind zijn ij de leeftijd van twee en een half of een volwassene die de basis van een vreemde taal wil leren. Er zijn nu 25 talen beschikbaar: Arabisch, Braziliaans Portugees, Tsjechisch, Deens, Nederlands, Brits Engels, VS Engels, Fonetisch Engels, Frans, Duits, Hebreeuws, Hongaars, Italiaans, Kannada, Nedersaksisch, Malayalam, Noors Bokmål, Punjabi, Luganda, Geromaniseerd Hindi, Russisch, Spaans, Slowaaks, Telugu en Oekraïens. KLettres biedt een speciaal gebruikersinterface en thema's voor jonge gebruikers.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">KLettres jest programem specjalnie zaprojektowanym do pomocy użytkownikowi przy nauce alfabetu w nowym języku, a następnie do nauki prostych sylab. Użytkownik może być małym dzieckiem w wieku dwóch i pół roku lub dorosłym, który chce się nauczyć podstaw obcego języka. Dostępnych jest dwadzieścia języków: Arabski, Czeski, Portugalski Brazylijski, Angielski Brytyjski, Duński, Holenderski, Angielski, Francuski, Niemiecki, Hebrajski, Węgierski, Włoski, Kanadyjski, Dolno saksoński, Luganda, Malayalam, Zromanizowany Hindi, Hiszpański, Słowacki, Telugu i Ukraiński. KLettres zapewnia własny układ sterowania programem i wystroje dla młodszych użytkowników.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O KLettres é uma aplicação desenhada especialmente para ajudar o utilizador a aprender o alfabeto numa nova língua e de depois aprender a ler sílabas simples. O utilizador poderá ser desde uma criança de dois anos até um adulto que deseje aprender as bases de uma língua estrangeira. Estão disponíveis de momento 25 línguas: Árabe, Português do Brasil, Checo, Dinamarquês, Holandês, Inglês Britânico, Inglês dos EUA, Inglês Fonético, Francês, Alemão, Hebraico, Húngaro, Italiano, Kannada, Baixo-Saxão, Malayalam, Norueguês Bokmål, Punjabi, Luganda, Hindu Romanizado, Russo, Espanhol, Eslovaco, Telugu e Ucraniano. O KLettres oferece uma interface de utilizador e temas especiais para os utilizadores mais novos.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">KLettres é um aplicativo especialmente desenvolvido para ajudar o usuário a aprender o alfabeto de um novo idioma e depois aprender a ler sílabas simples. O usuário pode ser uma criança de idade reduzida, a partir de dois anos e meio, até um adulto que só queira aprender as bases de um idioma estrangeiro. Existem 25 idiomas disponíveis: Árabe, Português do Brasil, Tcheco, Dinamarquês, Holandês, Inglês Britânico, Inglês dos EUA, Fonética de Inglês, Francês, Alemão, Hebraico, Húngaro, Italiano, Canarês, Baixo-Saxão, Malaiala, Norueguês, Panjabi, Luganda, Hindi Romanizado, Russo, Espanhol, Eslovaco, Telugu e Ucraniano. O KLettres oferece uma interface de usuário especial e temas infantis.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">KLettres je aplikácia špeciálne určená na pomoc pri výuke abecedy v novom jazyku a potom na naučenie čítania jednoduchých slabík. Používateľ môže byť malé dieťa od 2 a pol roka alebo dospelý, ktorý sa chce naučiť základy cudzieho jazyka. Aktuálne je dostupných 25 jazykov: arabčina, brazílska portugalčina, čeština, dánčina, holandčina, britská angličtina, americká angličtina, fonetická angličtina, francúzština, nemčina, hebrejčina, maďarčina, taliančina, kannadčina, dolná saština, malajalamčina, nórčina Bokmål, pandžábčina, lugandčina, romanizovaná hindčina, ruština, španielčina, slovenčina, telugčina a ukrajinčina. KLettres má špeciálne používateľské prostredie a témy pre mladších používateľov.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Klettres är ett program som är särskilt framtaget för att hjälpa användaren att lära sig alfabetet på ett nytt språk och sedan lära sig läsa enkla stavelser. Användaren kan vara ett litet barn från två och ett halvt år, eller en vuxen som vill lära sig grunderna i ett främmande språk. För närvarande är 25 språk är tillgängliga: amerikansk engelska, arabiska, brasiliansk portugisiska, brittisk engelska, danska, franska, hebreiska, holländska, italienska, kanaresiska, luganda, lågsaxiska, malayalam, norskt bokmål, phonics engelska, punjabi, romansk hindi, ryska, slovakiska, spanska, telugu, tjeckiska, tyska, ukrainska och ungerska.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">KLettres — це програма, спеціально розроблена для того, щоб допомогти користувачеві вивчити абетку нової мови, а потім навчитися читати прості склади. Користувачем може бути як дитина віком від двох з половиною років, так і доросла людина, яка бажає вивчити основи іноземної мови. У поточній версії ви можете скористатися такими двадцятьма п’ятьма мовами: арабська, бразильська португальська, чеська, данська, голландська, британська англійська, американська англійська, фонетична англійська, французька, німецька, іврит, угорська, італійська, каннада, нижньосаксонська, луганда, малаялам, латинізована гінді, іспанська, російська,словацька, телугу та українська.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxKLettres is an application specially designed to help the user to learn an alphabet in a new language and then to learn to read simple syllables. The user can be a young child aged from two and a half or an adult that wants to learn the basics of a foreign language. There are currently 25 languages available: Arabian, Brazilian Portuguese, Czech, Danish, Dutch, British English, US English, Phonics English, French, German, Hebrew, Hugarian, Italian, Kannada, Low Saxon, Malayalam, Norwegian Bokmål, Punjabi, Luganda, Romanized Hindi, Russian, Spanish, Slovak, Telugu and Ukrainian. KLettres provides a special user interface and themes for younger users.xx</p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">http://edu.kde.org/klettres/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=klettres</url>
  <url type="help">http://docs.kde.org/stable/en/kdeedu/klettres/index.html</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>http://kde.org/images/screenshots/klettres.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <provides>
    <binary>klettres</binary>
  </provides>
</component>
