<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>kmplot.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <name>KmPlot</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">KmPlot</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">KmPlot</name>
  <name xml:lang="nds">KmPlot</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">KmPlot</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">KmPlot</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">KmPlot</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">KmPlot</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">KmPlot</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Kmplot</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">KmPlot</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxKmPlotxx</name>
  <summary>Mathematical Function Plotter</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="cs">Matematický souřadnicový zapisovač funkcí</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Trazador de funciones matemáticas</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nds">Mathemaatsch Bagenschriever</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Plotprogramma voor wiskundige functies</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Program rysujący funkcje matematyczne</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Desenho de Funções Matemáticas</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Desenho de funções matemáticas</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Kreslenie matematických funkcií</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Matematisk funktionsritare</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Графобудівник математичних функцій</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxMathematical Function Plotterxx</summary>
  <description>
    <p>KmPlot is a program to plot graphs of functions, their integrals or derivatives. The graphs can be colorized and the view is highly configurable, is scalable, and can be zoomed. The program features a powerful mathematical parser, different plot types (cartesian, parametric, polar, implicit, differential), and provides simple mathematical tools like for finding maximum/minimum of a function. Parametrized functions can be visualized by adjusting the variable parameter via a slider. Plots can be exported as bitmap format pictures (BMP, PNG) and can be printed.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nds">Mit KmPlot laat sik se rutkamen Bagens vun Funkschonen un ehr Intrgralen un Afledden utgeven. De Bagens laat sik infarven un de Ansicht lett sik goot topassen, ok in de Grött. Dat Programm hett en deegt mathemaatsch Inleser, en Reeg verscheden Utgaavtypen (karteesch, parametersch, polaar, inbett, differenschell) un stellt en poor eenfache mathemaatsche Warktüüch praat, so as en Maximum/Minimum-Söker. Bi parametreert Funkschonen lett sik de Parameter mit en Schuver ännern. Utreekt Bagens laat sik as Pixelbiller (BMP, PNG) exporteren un drucken.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">KmPlot is een programma voor het plotten van grafieken van functies, hun integralen en afgeleiden. De grafieken kunnen worden gekleurd, en het beeld is in hoge mate configureerbaar, schaalbaar, en er kan in worden gezoomd. Het programma kan heel goed wiskundige formules lezen, kent diverse plottypes (cartesisch, parametrisch, polair, impliciet, differentieel), en heeft enkele eenvoudige wiskundige hulpmiddelen aan boord voor het vinden van de uiterste waarden (minimum en maximum) van een functie. Parametrische functies kunnen worden bekeken door de variabele parameter te wijzigen met behulp van een schuifbalk. Plots kunnen worden geëxporteerd als bitmaps (BMP, PNG), en kunnen worden afgedrukt.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">KmPlot jest programem do rysowania wykresów funkcji, ich całek i różniczek. Wykresy można zabarwiać, a widok jest wysoce ustawialny, skalowalny i można go powiększyć. Program dostarcza zaawansowany analizator składni matematycznej, różne rodzaje wykresów (kartezjański, parametryczny, biegunowy, jawny, różniczkowy) oraz proste narzędzia matematyczne jak np. do znajdowania maksimum/minimum funkcji. Funkcje parametryczne można przedstawić poprzez dostosowanie parametru zmiennej poprzez suwak. Wykresy można eksportować jako zdjęcia w postaci map bitowych (BMP lub PNG), można także je wydrukować.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O KmPlot é um programa para desenhar gráficos de funções, os seus integrais e derivadas. Os gráficos poderão ser coloridos e a área é bastante configurável, escalável e pode ser ampliada. O programa oferece um processador matemático poderoso, diferentes tipos de gráficos (cartesianos, paramétricos, polares, implícitos, diferenciais) e oferece ferramentas matemáticas simples como a descoberta dos valores máximos/mínimos de uma função. As funções parametrizadas podem ser visualizadas se ajustar o parâmetro variável com uma barra deslizante. Os gráficos podem ser exportados como imagens (BMP, PNG) e podem ser impressos.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">KmPlot é um programa para desenhar gráficos de funções, suas integrais e derivadas. Os gráficos podem ser coloridos e a área de visualização é bastante configurável, escalável e pode ser ampliada/reduzida. O programa possui um processador matemático poderoso, diferentes tipos de gráficos (cartesianos, paramétricos, polares, implícitos, diferenciais) e oferece ferramentas matemáticas simples, como a descoberta dos valores máximos/mínimos de uma função. As funções parametrizadas podem ser visualizadas se ajustar o parâmetro variável com uma barra deslizante. Os gráficos podem ser impressos e também exportados como imagens (BMP, PNG).</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">KmPlot je program na zakreslenie grafov funkcií, ich integrálov alebo derivácií. Grafy môžu byť zafarbené a pohľad je vysoko nastaviteľný, škálovateľný a je ho možné približovať. Program obsahuje silný matematický spracovač, rôzne typy zákresu (karteziánsky, parametrický, polárny, implicitný, diferenciálny) a poskytuje jednoduché matematické nástroje ako napríklad na hľadanie maxima/minima funkcie. Parametrizované funkcie je možné vizualizovať úpravou parametra premennej cez posuvník. Zákresy je možné exportovať ako obrázky bitmapového formátu (BMP, PNG) a je ich možné tlačiť.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Kmplot är ett program för att rita funktionsgrafer, deras integraler eller derivator. Graferna kan färgläggas och visningen är mycket inställningsbar, skalbar och kan zoomas. Programmet innehåller en kraftfull matematisk tolk, olika typer av diagram (kartesiska, parametriserade, polära, implicita, differentiella), och tillhandahåller enkla matematiska verktyg såsom att hitta maximum eller minimum av en funktion. Parametriserade funktioner kan åskådliggöras genom att justera den variabla parametern via ett skjutreglage. Diagram kan exporteras som bilder med bitavbildningsformat (BMP, PNG) och kan skrivas ut.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">KmPlot — програма для малювання графіків функцій, їхніх первісних або похідних. Передбачено можливість розфарбовування ліній графіків та гнучкі налаштування панелі перегляду з можливістю зміни масштабу та пересування області перегляду на площині. У програмі ви зможете скористатися потужним засобом обробки формул, накреслити графіки декількох типів (у декартовій та полярній системах координат, графіки функцій заданих параметрично, неявно, графіки похідних) та скористатися простими математичними інструментами, зокрема інструментом пошуку мінімумів та максимумів функції. Передбачено можливість роботи з параметризованими функціями, зміну параметра у яких можна здійснювати за допомогою повзунка змінної. Зображення графіків можна експортувати до файлів растрових зображень (BMP, PNG) та друкувати.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxKmPlot is a program to plot graphs of functions, their integrals or derivatives. The graphs can be colorized and the view is highly configurable, is scalable, and can be zoomed. The program features a powerful mathematical parser, different plot types (cartesian, parametric, polar, implicit, differential), and provides simple mathematical tools like for finding maximum/minimum of a function. Parametrized functions can be visualized by adjusting the variable parameter via a slider. Plots can be exported as bitmap format pictures (BMP, PNG) and can be printed.xx</p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">http://edu.kde.org/kmplot/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=kmplot</url>
  <url type="help">http://docs.kde.org/stable/en/kdeedu/kmplot/index.html</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>http://edu.kde.org/images/screenshots/kmplot.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <provides>
    <binary>kmplot</binary>
  </provides>
</component>
