<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>pairs.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <name>Pairs</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">Pexeso</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">Pairs</name>
  <name xml:lang="nds">Poren</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">Paren</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">Pary</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">Pairs</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">Pairs</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">Páry</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Par</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">Pairs</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxPairsxx</name>
  <summary>Memory Enhancement Game</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="cs">Hra k procvičování paměti</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Juego para la mejora de la memoria</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nds">Speel för't Verbetern vun't Behollen</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Geheugenoefenspel</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Gra na ćwiczenie pamięci</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Jogo de Exercícios de Memória</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Jogo para desenvolvimento da memória</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Hra na zlepšenie pamäte</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Spel för att förbättra minnet</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Гра для розвитку пам'яті</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxMemory Enhancement Gamexx</summary>
  <description>
    <p>Pairs is a collection of games aimed to help the development of preschool children. With these games the child can improve memory, logic, hearing, and even reading skills. Each game can have different themes so the child is stimulated with different and new challenges. It provides an editor to create own game sets.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nds">Poren is en Sett Spelen för Kinners, ehr se to School kaamt. Mit disse Spelen kann dat Kind dat Behollen, de Logik, dat Henhören un ok dat Lesen verbetern. Elkeen Speel kann verscheden Mustern hebben, dat Kind beleevt dor verscheden Rutföddern mit. Dat gifft ok en Editor, mit den sik egen Spelen opstellen laat.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Paren is een verzameling spellen gericht op het helpen van de ontwikkeling van voorschoolse kinderen. Met deze spellen kan het kind zijn geheugen, logica, horen en zelfs leesvaardigheid verbeteren. Elk spel kan verschillende thema's hebben zodat het kind gestimuleerd wordt door verschillende en nieuwe uitdagingen. Het biedt een bewerker om eigen sets spellen te ontwikkelen.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Pary jest zbiorem gier przeznaczonych do wspomagania rozwoju dzieci w wieku przedszkolnym. Z pomocą tych gier dzieci mogą poprawić pamięć, logikę, słuchanie, a nawet umiejętności czytania. Każda gra ma różne wystroje, więc dziecko jest stymulowana różnymi i nowymi wyzwaniami. Program dostarcza edytor do tworzenia własnych zestawów gier. </p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O Pairs é uma colecção de jogos destinados a ajudar no desenvolvimento pré-escolar das crianças. Com estes jogos, a criança poderá melhorar a memória, a lógica, a audição e até mesmo algumas aptidões de leitura. Cada jogo poderá ter diferentes temas, de modo que a criança seja estimulada com desafios diferentes e novos. Oferece um editor para criar conjuntos de jogos próprios.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Pairs é uma coleção de jogos destinados a ajudar no desenvolvimento das crianças em idade pré-escolar. Com esses jogos, a criança poderá melhorar a memória, lógica, audição e até mesmo algumas aptidões de leitura. Cada jogo poderá ter diferentes temas, de modo que a criança seja estimulada com desafios diferentes. Ele oferece um editor para criar os próprios conjuntos de jogos.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Pairs je kolekcia hier zameraných na pomoc s vývojom predškolských detí. S týmito hrami si dieťa môže zlepšiť pamäť, logiku, počúvanie a dokonca čítanie. Každá hra môže mať rôzne témy a stimuluje dieťa na rôzne a nové výzvy. Poskytuje editor na vytváranie vlastných sád hier.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Par är en samling spel med mål att hjälpa barn i förskoleålder utvecklas. Med dessa spel kan barnet förbättra minne, logik, hörsel och till och med läsfärdighet. Varje spel kan ha olika teman så att barnet kan stimuleras med olika och nya utmaningar. En editor för att skapa egna speluppsättningar tillhandahålls. </p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Pairs — набір ігор, які розроблено, щоб допомогти у розвитку дошкільнят. Ці ігри можуть покращити пам’ять, логічні здібності, слух та навички читання дитини. Для кожної з ігор передбачено різні теми, отже дитина постійно поставатиме перед новими викликами. Передбачено редактор для створення власних наборів ігор.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxPairs is a collection of games aimed to help the development of preschool children. With these games the child can improve memory, logic, hearing, and even reading skills. Each game can have different themes so the child is stimulated with different and new challenges. It provides an editor to create own game sets.xx</p>
    <p>Games:</p>
    <p xml:lang="cs">Hry:</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Juegos:</p>
    <p xml:lang="nds">Spelen:</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Spellen:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Gry:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">Jogos:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Jogos:</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Hry:</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Spel:</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Ігри:</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxGames:xx</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Pairs: A game for the development of memory skills. On a board there are different cards, all facing down, so the player does not see the pictures. Each card matches only one other card that has the same exact picture. The player has to click a card to turn it and try to remember where the match is. When a match is found both cards stay uncovered and the player gets a point. </li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Poren: En Speel för't Öven vun't Behollen. Op en Disch gifft dat en Reeg Koorten, all mit de Böversiet na nerrn. De Speler kann also de Biller dor op nich ankieken. Elkeen Koort höört jüst nau een anner Koort mit jüst dat sülve Bild dor op to. De Speler mutt dor op klicken un versöcht dat un markt sik, woneem de tohören Koort liggen deit. Hett he en Poor funnen, blievt de Koorten opdeckt un de Speler kriggt en Punkt.</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Paren: een spel voor het ontwikkelen van de geheugenfunctie. Op een bord bevinden zich verschillende omgekeerde kaarten, zodat de speler de plaatjes niet kan zien. Elke kaart komt overeen met slechts één andere kaart die exact hetzelfde plaatje bevat. De speler moet op een kaart klikken om deze om te draaien en proberen te herinneren waar de overeenkomstige is. Wanneer er een overeenkomst is gevonden tussen beide kaarten dan blijven ze onbedekt liggen en krijgt de speler een punt.</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Pary: Gra na polepszenie zdolności zapamiętywania. Na planszy umieszczono różne karty, wszystkie nieodkryte, tak że gracz nie widzi zdjęć. Każda karta pasuje tylko do jednej innej karty, która ma dokładnie to samo zdjęcie. Gracz musi nacisnąć na kartę, aby ją obrócić i zapamiętać w przypadku znalezienia drugiej pasującej. Gdy uda się od razu znaleźć pasującą kartę, to obie pozostaną odkryte, a gracz zdobywa punkt.</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Pares: Um jogo para o desenvolvimento de aptidões de memória. Num tabuleiro existem diferentes cartões, todos virados de baixo, de forma que o jogador não veja as imagens. Cada cartão corresponderá a outro se tiver exactamente a mesma imagem. O jogador tem de carregar num cartão para o virar e tentar-se recordar onde está a correspondência. Quando for encontrado um cartão correspondente, ambas as cartas ficam a descoberto e o jogador recebe um ponto.</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Pares: Um jogo para desenvolvimento de aptidões da memória. Em um tabuleiro existem diferentes cartões, todos virados com a face para baixo, de forma que o jogador não veja as figuras. Cada cartão formará par com apenas um outro cartão com exatamente a mesma figura. O jogador precisa clicar em um cartão para virá-lo e tentar lembrar onde está o seu par. Quando for encontrado um cartão que corresponde ao seu par, ambos os cartões ficam virados e o jogador ganha um ponto.</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Pairs: Hra pre vývoj pamäťových schopností. Na doske sú rôzne karty, všetky tvárou dolu, teda hráč nevidí obrázky. Každá karta má iba jednu ďalšiu, ktorá má rovnaký obrázok. Hráč musí kliknúť na kartu na jej otočenie a snažiť sa zapamätať si ju. Keď hráč nájde zhodu, obe karty sa odkryjú a hráč získava bod.</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Par: Ett spel för utveckling av minnesfärdigheter. Olika kort finns på ett bräde, alla med framsidan nedåt så att spelaren inte ser bilderna. Varje kort passar bara ihop med ett annat kort som har exakt samma bild. Spelaren ska klicka på ett kort för att vända det och försöka komma ihåg var motsvarigheten finns. När en motsvarighet hittas förblir båda korten avtäckta och spelaren får en poäng.</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Пари: гра для розвитку навичок запам’ятовування. На полі для гри буде показано перевернені картки, отже гравець не бачитиме зображеного на картках. У кожної з карток є пара з таким самим зображенням. Гравцеві слід натискати картки для перевертання однієї картки і запам’ятовувати зображення, виявляючи при цьому пари карток. Якщо буде послідовно перевернуто дві парні картки, програма залишить картки перевернутими зображенням до гравця, а гравець отримає переможне очко.</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxPairs: A game for the development of memory skills. On a board there are different cards, all facing down, so the player does not see the pictures. Each card matches only one other card that has the same exact picture. The player has to click a card to turn it and try to remember where the match is. When a match is found both cards stay uncovered and the player gets a point.xx</li>
      <li>Relations: A game for the development of memory and logic skills. On a board there are different cards, all facing down, so the player does not see the pictures. Each card matches only one other card with a picture that is somehow related to the first. The player has to click a card to turn it and try to remember where the match is. When a match is found both cards stay uncovered and the player gets a point. </li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Betöög: En Speel för't Öven vun't Behollen un vun de Logik. Op en Disch gifft dat en Reeg Koorten, all mit de Böversiet na nerrn. De Speler kann also de Biller dor op nich ankieken. Elkeen Koort höört een anner Koort mit en Bild dor op to, dat wat mit dat eerste Bild to doon hett. De Speler mutt dor op klicken un versöcht dat un markt sik, woneem de tohören Koort liggen deit. Hett he en Poor funnen, blievt de Koorten opdeckt un de Speler kriggt en Punkt.</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Relaties: een spel voor het ontwikkelen van het geheugen en de logica. Op een bord bevinden zich verschillende omgekeerde kaarten, zodat de speler de plaatjes niet kan zien. Elke kaart komt overeen met slechts één andere kaart die een plaatje bevat dat op de een of andere manier gerelateerd is met het eerste. De speler moet op een kaart klikken om deze om te draaien en proberen te herinneren waar de overeenkomstige is. Wanneer er een overeenkomst is gevonden tussen beide kaarten dan blijven ze onbedekt liggen en krijgt de speler een punt.</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Związki: Gra do polepszenia zdolności zapamiętywania i umiejętności logicznego myślenia. Na planszy umieszczono różne karty, wszystkie nieodkryte, tak że gracz nie widzi zdjęć. Każda karta pasuje tylko do jednej innej karty, która ma zdjęcie w jakiś sposób odnoszące się do tej pierwszej. Gracz musi nacisnąć na kartę, aby ją obrócić i zapamiętać w przypadku znalezienia drugiej pasującej. Gdy uda się od razu znaleźć pasującą kartę, to obie pozostaną odkryte, a gracz zdobywa punkt.</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Relações: Um jogo para o desenvolvimento de aptidões lógicas e de memória. Num tabuleiro existem cartões diferentes, todos virados para baixo, de modo que o jogador não veja as imagens. Cada cartão irá corresponder a outro, caso este último tenha uma imagem relacionada de alguma forma com a primeira. O jogador terá de carregar num cartão para o virar e tentar-se recordar onde está a correspondência. Quando for encontrado um cartão correspondente, ambas as cartas ficam a descoberto e o jogador recebe um ponto.</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Relações: Um jogo para desenvolvimento de aptidões lógicas e de memória. Em um tabuleiro existem diferentes cartões, todos virados com a face para baixo, de modo que o jogador não veja as figuras. Cada cartão formará par com apenas um outro cartão, que de alguma forma estiver relacionado com o primeiro. O jogador precisa clicar em um cartão para virá-lo e tentar lembrar onde está o seu par. Quando for encontrado um cartão que correspondente ao seu par, ambos os cartões ficam virados e o jogador ganha um ponto.</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Vzťahy: Hra pre rozvoj pamäťových a logických zručností. Na doske sú rôzne karty, všetky tvárou dolu, teda hráč ich nevidí. Každá karta súvisí s inou tak, že jej obrázok nejako súvisí s prvým. Hráč má kliknúť na kartu na jej otočenie a snažiť sa zapamätať si ju. Ak hráč nájde zhodu, obe karty ostanú odkryté a hráč získava bod.</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Relationer: Ett spel för utveckling av minnes- och logikfärdigheter Olika kort finns på ett bräde, alla med framsidan nedåt så att spelaren inte ser bilderna. Varje kort passar bara ihop med ett annat kort som är relaterat till det första på något sätt. Spelaren ska klicka på ett kort för att vända det och försöka komma ihåg var motsvarigheten finns. När en motsvarighet hittas förblir båda korten avtäckta och spelaren får en poäng.</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Зв’язки: гра для розвитку навичок запам’ятовування і логіки. На полі для гри буде показано перевернені картки, отже гравець не бачитиме зображеного на картках. У кожної з карток є пара з певним чином пов’язаним зображенням. Гравцеві слід натискати картки для перевертання однієї картки і запам’ятовувати зображення, виявляючи при цьому пари карток. Якщо буде послідовно перевернуто дві парні картки, програма залишить картки перевернутими зображенням до гравця, а гравець отримає переможне очко.</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxRelations: A game for the development of memory and logic skills. On a board there are different cards, all facing down, so the player does not see the pictures. Each card matches only one other card with a picture that is somehow related to the first. The player has to click a card to turn it and try to remember where the match is. When a match is found both cards stay uncovered and the player gets a point.xx</li>
      <li>Logic: A game for the development of logic skills. On a board there are different cards, all facing up, and the player can see all the pictures. Each card matches with only one card with a picture that is somehow related to the first. The player has to find the different matches. When a match is found both cards stay uncovered and the player get a point.</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Logik: En Speel för't Öven vun de Logik. Op en Disch gifft dat en Reeg Koorten, all mit de Böversiet na baven. De Speler kann also all de Biller dor op ankieken. Elkeen Koort höört een anner Koort mit en Bild dor op to, dat wat mit dat eerste Bild to doon hett. De Speler mutt de tohören Koort finnen. Hett he en Poor funnen, blievt de Koorten opdeckt un de Speler kriggt en Punkt.</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Logica: een spel voor de ontwikkeling van de logica. Op een bord bevinden zich verschillende omhoog liggende kaarten en de speler kan alle plaatjes zien. Elke kaart komt overeen met slechts één kaart met een plaatje dat op de een of andere manier gerelateerd is aan de eerste. De speler moet de verschillende overeenkomsten vinden. Bij het vinden van een overeenkomst blijven beide kaard=ten onbedekt en de speler krijgt een punt.</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Logika: Gra na polepszenie umiejętności logicznego myślenia. Na planszy umieszczono różne karty, wszystkie odkryte, tak że gracz widzi wszystkie  zdjęcia. Każda karta pasuje tylko do jednej innej karty, która ma zdjęcie w jakiś sposób odnoszące się do tej pierwszej. Gracz musi wskazać różne pasujące karty. Gdy uda wskazać pasującą kartę, to obie pozostaną odkryte, a gracz zdobywa punkt.</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Lógica: Um jogo para o desenvolvimento de aptidões lógicas e de memória. Num tabuleiro existem cartões diferentes, todos virados para cima, de modo que o jogador possa ver as imagens. Cada cartão irá corresponder a outro, caso este último tenha uma imagem relacionada de alguma forma com a primeira. O jogador terá de descobrir as diferentes correspondências. Quando for encontrado um cartão correspondente, ambas as cartas ficam a descoberto e o jogador recebe um ponto.</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Lógica: Um jogo para desenvolvimento de aptidões lógicas e de memória. Em um tabuleiro existem diferentes cartões, todos virados com a face para cima, de modo que o jogador possa ver as figuras. Cada cartão formará par com apenas um outro cartão, que de alguma forma estiver relacionado com o primeiro. O jogador precisa identificar as diferentes correspondências. Quando for encontrado um cartão que correspondente ao seu par, ambos os cartões ficam virados para cima e o jogador ganha um ponto.</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Logika: Hra pre rozvod logických zručností. Na doske sú rôzne karty, všetky tvárou dolu, teda hráč ich nevidí. Každá karta vyhovuje iba jednej inej karte s obrázkom, ktorý nejako súvisí s prvým. Hráč má nájsť iné zhody. Ak sa nájde zhoda, obe karty ostanú odkryté a hráč získava bod.</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Logik: Ett spel för utveckling av logikfärdigheter. Olika kort finns på ett bräde, alla med framsidan upp så att spelaren kan se alla bilder. Varje kort hör bara ihop med ett annat kort med en bild som är relaterat till det första på något sätt. Spelaren ska hitta de olika motsvarigheterna. När en motsvarighet hittas förblir båda korten avtäckta och spelaren får en poäng.</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Логіка: гра для розвитку навичок із логіки. На полі для гри буде показано картки так, щоб гравець бачив зображене на картках. У кожної з карток є пара з певним чином пов’язаним зображенням. Гравцеві слід знайти відповідники карток і натиснути їх. Якщо буде послідовно натиснуто дві парні картки, гравець отримає переможне очко.</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxLogic: A game for the development of logic skills. On a board there are different cards, all facing up, and the player can see all the pictures. Each card matches with only one card with a picture that is somehow related to the first. The player has to find the different matches. When a match is found both cards stay uncovered and the player get a point.xx</li>
      <li>Sound: A game for the development of memory and hearing skills. On a board there are different cards, all facing down, so the player does not see the content. There are two types of cards, one type has a picture and the other type will play a sound when selected. The player has to find the right sound that matches each picture. When a match is found both card stay uncovered and the player gets a point. </li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Klang: En Speel för't Öven vun't Behollen un vun't Henhören. Op en Disch gifft dat en Reeg Koorten, all mit de Böversiet na nerrn. De Speler kann also de Biller dor op nich ankieken. Dat gifft twee Oorden Koorten, op de een sünd Biller un bi de anner Oort warrt en Klang afspeelt, wenn een dor en vun utsöken deit. De Speler mutt den Klang finnen, de elkeen Bild tohöört. Hett he en Poor funnen, blievt de Koorten opdeckt un de Speler kriggt en Punkt.</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Geluid: een spel voor de ontwikkeling van geheugen en horen. Op een bord bevinden zich verschillende omgedraaide kaarten, zodat de speler de inhoud niet kan zien. Er zijn twee typen kaarten, een type bevat een plaatje en het andere type zal een geluid afspelen bij selectie. De speler moet het juiste geluid vinden dat overeenkomt met elk plaatje. Bij het vinden van een overeenkomst blijven beide kaarten onbedekt en de speler krijgt een punt.</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Dźwięk: Gra na polepszenie zdolności zapamiętywania i umiejętności słuchania. Na planszy umieszczono różne karty, wszystkie nieodkryte, tak że gracz nie widzi ich zawartości. Istnieją dwa rodzaje kart, jeden zawiera zdjęcia, a drugi dźwięki. Gracz ma za zadanie znaleźć dźwięk pasujący do zdjęcia na karcie i tak dla każdej karty. Gdy uda się znaleźć pasujące karty, to obie pozostaną odkryte, a gracz zdobywa punkt.</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Som: Um jogo para o desenvolvimento de aptidões auditivas e de memória. Num tabuleiro existem cartões diferentes, todos virados para baixo, de modo que o jogador não veja o conteúdo. Existem dois tipos de cartões, onde um tem uma imagem e o outro irá tocar um som quando for seleccionado. O jogador terá de descobrir o som correcto que corresponde a cada imagem. Quando for encontrado um cartão correspondente, ambas as cartas ficam a descoberto e o jogador recebe um ponto.</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Som: Um jogo para desenvolvimento de aptidões auditivas e de memória. Em um tabuleiro existem diferentes cartões, todos virados com a face para baixo, de modo que o jogador não veja o conteúdo. Existem dois tipos de cartões, onde um tem uma figura e o outro irá tocar um som quando for selecionado. O jogador precisa encontrar o som correto que corresponde a cada figura. Quando for encontrado um cartão correspondente, ambos os cartões ficam virados para cima e o jogador ganha um ponto.</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Zvuk: Hra pre rozvoj pamäťových a počúvacích schopností. Na doske sú rôzne karty, všetky tvárou dolu, teda hráč nevidí ich obsah. Sú dva druhy kariet, jeden typ má obrázok a druhý prehrá zvuk pri výbere. Hráč musí nájsť správny zvuk, ktorý vyhovuje každému obrázku. Ak sa nájde zhoda, obe karty ostanú odkryté a hráč získava bod.</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Ljud: Ett spel för utveckling av minnes- och hörselfärdigheter. Olika kort finns på ett bräde, alla med framsidan nedåt så att spelaren inte ser innehållet. Det finns två typer av kort, den ena typen har en bild och den andra spelar ett ljud när det väljes. Spelaren ska hitta rätt ljud som hör ihop med varje bild. När en motsvarighet hittas förblir båda korten avtäckta och spelaren får en poäng.</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Звук: гра для розвитку навичок запам’ятовування і логіки. На полі для гри буде показано перевернені картки, отже гравець не бачитиме зображеного на картках. У кожної з карток є пара з певним чином пов’язаним зображенням. Гравцеві слід натискати картки для перевертання однієї картки і запам’ятовувати зображення, виявляючи при цьому пари карток. Якщо буде послідовно перевернуто дві парні картки, програма залишить картки перевернутими зображенням до гравця, а гравець отримає переможне очко.</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxSound: A game for the development of memory and hearing skills. On a board there are different cards, all facing down, so the player does not see the content. There are two types of cards, one type has a picture and the other type will play a sound when selected. The player has to find the right sound that matches each picture. When a match is found both card stay uncovered and the player gets a point.xx</li>
      <li>SoundLogic: A game for the development of hearing skills. On a board there are different cards, all facing up. There are two types of cards, one type has a picture and the other type will play a sound when selected. The player has to find the right sound that matches the right picture. When a match is found both cards stay uncovered and the player gets a point. </li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Klanglogik: En Speel för't Öven vun't Henhören. Op en Disch gifft dat en Reeg Koorten, all mit de Böversiet na baven. Dat gifft twee Oorden Koorten, op de een sünd Biller un bi de anner Oort warrt en Klang afspeelt, wenn een dor en vun utsöken deit. De Speler mutt den Klang finnen, de elkeen Bild tohöört. Hett he en Poor funnen, blievt de Koorten opdeckt un de Speler kriggt en Punkt.</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Logica met geluid: een spel om de vaardigheid van het herkennen van geluiden te ontwikkelen. Op een bord bevinden zich twee typen kaarten, één kaart heeft een plaatje en het andere type speelt bij selectie een geluid. De speler moet het juiste geluid vinden dat overeenkomt met het juiste plaatje. Wanneer een overeenkomst is gevonden blijven beide kaarten omhoog liggen en de speler krijgt een punt.</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Logika dźwięku: Gra na polepszenie umiejętności słuchania. Na planszy umieszczono różne karty, wszystkie odkryte. Istnieją dwa rodzaje kart, jeden zawiera zdjęcia, a drugi dźwięki. Gracz ma za zadanie znaleźć dźwięk pasujący do zdjęcia na karcie i tak dla każdej karty. Gdy uda się znaleźć pasujące karty, to obie pozostaną odkryte, a gracz zdobywa punkt.</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Som-Lógica: Um jogo para o desenvolvimento de aptidões auditivas. Num tabuleiro existem cartões diferentes, todos virados para cima. Existem dois tipos de cartões, onde um tem uma imagem e o outro irá tocar um som quando for seleccionado. O jogador terá de descobrir o som correcto que corresponde à imagem correcta. Quando for encontrado um cartão correspondente, ambas as cartas se mantêm a descoberto e o jogador recebe um ponto.</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Som-Lógica: Um jogo para desenvolvimento de aptidões auditivas. Em um tabuleiro existem diferentes cartões, todos virados com a face para cima. Existem dois tipos de cartões, onde um tem uma figura e o outro irá tocar um som quando for selecionado. O jogador precisa encontrar o som correto que corresponde à figura. Quando for encontrada uma correspondência, ambos os cartões ficam virados para cima e o jogador ganha um ponto.</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">SoundLogic: Hra pre rozvoj pamäťových a počúvacích schopností. Na doske sú rôzne karty, všetky tvárou dolu, teda hráč nevidí ich obsah. Sú dva druhy kariet, jeden typ má obrázok a druhý prehrá zvuk pri výbere. Hráč musí nájsť správny zvuk, ktorý vyhovuje každému obrázku. Ak sa nájde zhoda, obe karty ostanú odkryté a hráč získava bod.</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Ljudlogik: Ett spel för utveckling av hörselfärdigheter. Olika kort finns på ett bräde, alla med framsidan upp. Det finns två typer av kort, den ena typen har en bild och den andra spelar ett ljud när det väljes. Spelaren ska hitta rätt ljud som hör ihop med varje bild. När en motsvarighet hittas förblir båda korten avtäckta och spelaren får en poäng.</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Звук і логіка: гра для розвитку слухових навичок. На полі для гри буде показано картки так, щоб гравець бачив зображене на картках. Передбачено два типи карток: на одному показано зображення, а інший відтворює звук після натискання. Гравцеві слід знайти картки, зображення і звук яких є відповідними. Якщо буде послідовно натиснуто дві парні картки, гравець отримає переможне очко.</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxSoundLogic: A game for the development of hearing skills. On a board there are different cards, all facing up. There are two types of cards, one type has a picture and the other type will play a sound when selected. The player has to find the right sound that matches the right picture. When a match is found both cards stay uncovered and the player gets a point.xx</li>
      <li>Words: A game to develop the memory and reading skills of the child. On a board there are different cards all facing down so the player does not see the content. There are two types of cards, one card has a picture and another card has a word. The player has to find the right word that matches the right picture. When a match is found both cards stay uncovered and the player get a point.</li>
      <li xml:lang="nds">Wöör: En Speel för't Öven vun't Behollen un vun't Lesen. Op en Disch gifft dat en Reeg Koorten, all mit de Böversiet na nerrn. De Speler kann also de Biller dor op nich ankieken. Dat gifft twee Oorden Koorten, op de een sünd Biller un op de anner Oort steiht en Woort. De Speler mutt dat Woort finnen, dat elkeen Bild tohöört. Hett he en Poor funnen, blievt de Koorten opdeckt un de Speler kriggt en Punkt.</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Woorden: een spel om het geheugen en leesvaardigheid van het kind te ontwikkelen. Op een bord bevinden zich verschillende omgedraaide kaarten, zodat de speler de inhoud niet kan zien. Er zijn twee typen kaarten, één kaart heeft een plaatje en een andere kaart bevat een woord. De speler moet het juiste woord vinden dat overeenkomt met het juiste plaatje. Wanneer een overeenkomst is gevonden blijven beide kaarten omhoog liggen en de speler krijgt een punt.</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Słowa: Gra na polepszenie zdolności zapamiętywania oraz umiejętności czytania. Na planszy umieszczono różne karty, wszystkie nieodkryte, tak że gracz nie widzi zawartości. Istnieją dwa rodzaje kart, jeden zawiera zdjęcia, a drugi słowa. Gracz ma za zadanie znaleźć słowo pasujące do zdjęcia na karcie i tak dla każdej karty. Gdy uda się znaleźć pasujące karty, to obie pozostaną odkryte, a gracz zdobywa punkt.</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Palavras: Um jogo para o desenvolvimento de aptidões lógicas e de leitura. Num tabuleiro existem cartões diferentes, todos virados para baixo, de modo que o jogador não veja o conteúdo. Existem dois tipos de cartões, onde um tem uma imagem e o outro tem uma palavra. O jogador terá de descobrir a palavra correcta que corresponde à imagem correcta. Quando for encontrado um cartão correspondente, ambas as cartas manter-se-ão a descoberto e o jogador recebe um ponto.</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Palavras: Um jogo para desenvolvimento da memória e aptidões de leitura da criança. Em um tabuleiro existem diferentes cartões, todos virados com a face para baixo, de modo que o jogador não veja o conteúdo. Existem dois tipos de cartões, onde um tem uma figura e o outro tem uma palavra. O jogador deve encontrar a palavra que corresponde à figura. Quando for encontrado um cartão correspondente, ambos os cartões ficam virados para cima e o jogador ganha um ponto.</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Slová: Hra na rozvoj pamäťových a čítačích zručnosti dieťaťa. Na doske sú rôzne karty všetky tvárou dolu, teda hráč ich nevidí. Sú dva typy kariet, jedna karta má obrázok a druhá má slovo. Hráč musí nájsť správne slovo, ktoré vyhovuje správnemu obrázku. Ak sa nájde zhoda, obe karty ostanú odkryté a hráč získava bod.</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Ord: Ett spel för att utveckla ett barns minnes- och läsfärdighet. Olika kort finns på ett bräde, alla med framsidan nedåt så att spelaren inte ser innehållet. Det finns två typer av kort, den ena typen har en bild och den andra har ett ord. Spelaren ska hitta rätt ord som hör ihop med varje bild. När en motsvarighet hittas förblir båda korten avtäckta och spelaren får en poäng.</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Слова: гра для розвитку навичок запам’ятовування і читання. На полі для гри буде показано картки так, щоб гравець не бачив зображене на картках. Передбачено два типи карток: на одному показано зображення, а на іншому — записане слово. Гравцеві слід знайти картки, зображення і слово яких є відповідними. Якщо буде послідовно натиснуто дві парні картки, гравець отримає переможне очко.</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxWords: A game to develop the memory and reading skills of the child. On a board there are different cards all facing down so the player does not see the content. There are two types of cards, one card has a picture and another card has a word. The player has to find the right word that matches the right picture. When a match is found both cards stay uncovered and the player get a point.xx</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">http://edu.kde.org/pairs/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=pairs</url>
  <url type="help">http://docs.kde.org/development/en/kdeedu/pairseditor/index.html</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>http://edu.kde.org/images/screenshots/resized/pairs.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <provides>
    <binary>pairs</binary>
  </provides>
</component>
