<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<application>
    <id type="desktop">tagtool.desktop</id>
    <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
    <name>Audio Tag Tool</name>
    <summary>Ogg Vorbis and MP3 tag manager</summary>
    <description>
        <p>
            Audio Tag Tool is a program to manage the information fields in MP3 and 
            Ogg Vorbis files (commonly called 'tags').  It is available under the GNU 
            General Public Licence (GPL).  Please send me any comments or bugs you 
            find.
        </p>
        <p>
            Tag Tool can be used to edit tags one by one, but the most useful 
            features are the ability to easily tag or rename hundreds of files at 
            once, in any desired format.
        </p>
        <p>
            The interface is arranged into two sections, with the list of available 
            files on the left and a set of tabs on the right. Each tab corresponds to 
            one of the main operations Audio Tag Tool can do:
        </p>
            <ul>
                <li>Lets you edit the tags individually</li>
                <li>You can set the tags of multiple files at once</li>
                <li>The tag fields can be set to a fixed value, filled in from the file's name, or left alone</li>
                <li>Allows you to remove the tags from multiple files at once</li>
                <li>For MP3 files it lets you choose to remove only ID3v1 or ID3v2 tags</li>
                <li>You can rename multiple files at once and/or organize them into directories</li>
                <li>Generates playlists. Playlists can be sorted by file name or by any tag field</li>
            </ul>
        <p>
            The mass tag and mass rename features can handle filenames in any 
            format thanks to an easily configurable format template. 
        </p>
    </description>
    <!-- No screenshots :( -->
    <url type="homepage">https://github.com/tagtool/tagtool</url>
    <updatecontact>ms@ansta.lt</updatecontact>
</application>

